magix-website.com 2016-12-07

# Privacy Statement > MAGIX Online World

We appreciate your trust in us and always take the greatest possible care to protect your personal data from unauthorized access using the highest safety standards possible.

Your order, personal information and payment details are protected by technical security systems and additional authorization procedures. This applies to the transfer of your data as well as to its storage on our servers. Your safety concerns according to the statutory obligations will always be accounted for when data is saved. We process your personal information for handling orders and maintaining customer relations.

**What information does MAGIX collect?**

Within the frame of processing the services ordered by you, MAGIX, as necessary, collects information such as your name, address and, if applicable, your bank details and email address for the duration of the contractual relationship between you and MAGIX. Your data will be collected exclusively for processing the corresponding order and will be deleted according to statutory requirements as soon as it is no longer needed. Depending on the payment method the payment provider may ask for your phone number during the ordering process for identification purposes.

Provided you receive our newsletter you can revoke the future use your email address for advertising purposes at any time by clicking "Unsubscribe" at the bottom of the newsletter.

**Repeating the declaration of consent for the newsletter:**

The following consent was expressly granted by you and we recorded your consent. Due to the Telemedia Act all content regarding consent must be readily available.

_"Please enter the following data to order our newsletter.  
Title:  
First name:  
Surname:  
Country:  
Email address:  
You can cancel any future use of your email address for advertising purposes at any time by clicking "Unsubscribe" at the bottom of the newsletter."_

**Where does MAGIX save your data?**

The information we have collected from you is stored exclusively on our company-owned servers. Sensitive information is encrypted during transfer using established safety technology (SSL: Secure Socket Layer) and thereby protected from unauthorized access.

**Does MAGIX disclose your data to third parties?**

On this website Google Analytics, a web analysis service by Google Inc, gathers and saves data from which user profiles are created using pseudonyms. These user profiles serve to analyze visitor behavior and are evaluated in order to improve the design of our offers in line with demand.

In addition we also use Google remarketing technology on our website. This technology allows users that have already visited our website and are interested in products to be targeted by specific advertisements. This benefits the users because they will receive advertisements that suit their interest, this also allows us to recommend suitable products.

Cookies are used for Google Analytics and for Google remarketing technology. These are small text files which are saved locally on the computer of the person visiting the site, they enable our website to recognize the user the next time they visit our website. You can prevent cookies being installed by selecting the respective option in your browser software; we would like to make it clear however that it is necessary to allow cookies in order to use the Service Center and web shop, other areas of the website work without cookies. The pseudonymized user profiles will not be merged with personal data regarding the bearer of the pseudonym without expressly stated approval by those affected. You can object to the collection and saving of data for web analysis purposes at any time by installing the deactivation add-on for your browser provided by Google . The add-on, plus more detailed information can be found using the following link: [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.  
](http://www.magix-online.com/tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)  
Using a corresponding code extension, Google Analytics captures your IP address on our website, but in an anonymous form.

On these web pages plug-ins from the social network facebook.com are used, which is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook").

If you access Internet pages provided by our website with this kind of plug-in, a link to the Facebook servers will be created and a plug-in will be displayed on the website by notifying your browser. Thereby notifying the Facebook servers which of our websites you have visited. If you are logged in as a member of Facebook, Facebook assigns this information to your personal Facebook account. When using plug-in functions (such as clicking on the "Like" button, or when leaving a comment) this information is associated with your Facebook account, you can prevent this by logging out before using the plug-in.

Please consult Facebook's privacy policy for more detailed information on your rights and ways to protect your privacy and how Facebook collects and uses data, which you can read about at [http://www.facebook.com/policy.php.  
](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php)  
**The following applies in other cases:**

MAGIX or companies affiliated with MAGIX may use the information collected from you for marketing purposes, provided you have given your consent to such utilization. You can object to your data being used for commercial purposes at any time. If you wish to do so please write an email to [privacy@magix.net](mailto:privacy@magix.net).

Moreover, your details may be passed on to third parties for providing services or for delivering the newsletter, for instance, to the carrier who will deliver the goods you have ordered or the company that will be responsible for the technology for delivering the newsletter.

Within the frame of applicable law MAGIX will surrender information to law enforcement agencies and courts at their request for the purpose of criminal prosecution.

**Does MAGIX use cookies?**

MAGIX does not collect personal data of any kind when you visit our website. However MAGIX places cookies when its website is loaded thus avoiding anew requesting of information on navigating our website.

Cookies are small files that are saved on the hard drive of your PC. Access therefore only occurs in impersonalized form and exclusively when you visit our website. Other websites cannot access this information.

Most cookies we use are deleted at the end of the browsing session (known as session cookies). Other cookies stay on your computer and allow us to recognize your computer on your next visit (persistent cookies). Our partner companies are not permitted to gather, process or use personal data collected from our website using cookies.

You can prevent cookies from being installed at anytime by selecting the option "Do not accept cookies" in your browser.

Data that we collect with the aid of cookies is used for the sole purpose of customizing our offer according to customer preferences and to make browsing of our site as convenient as possible for you.

It is necessary to allow cookies in order to use the Service Center and web shop, other areas of the website however will be displayed without cookies.

**Cookies from third party providers:**

MAGIX operates an affiliate program to attract customers. To this end we place banners and/or links to our Online Shop on third party (affiliate) websites. You will be redirected to our Online Shop if you click on one of these links and/or banners. Using a third party cookie we can ascertain which affiliate redirected you. This does not provide us with any of your personal information.

MAGIX uses services from third parties to optimize its website. This logs your behavior on our website using cookies. Personal information will not be used.
